- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
All:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[flute plays]
[长笛演奏]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[eerie electronic music]
[诡异的电子音乐]
♪ ♪
- Thank you for attending
today's time capsule ceremony.
- 感谢您的出席
今天的时间胶囊仪式。
It's important that future
generations know what
重要的是未来
几代人都知道什么
made Bikini Bottom special,
its citizens and their
使比基尼泳裤变得特别，
它的公民和他们的
random personal belongings.
随机的个人物品。
[cheering]
[欢呼]
And now, please welcome
Miss Sandy Cheeks.
现在，请欢迎
桑迪·奇克斯小姐。
- Thank you, Miss Mayor.
- 谢谢你，市长小姐。
I designed this metallic
vessel to perfectly
我设计了这个金属
容器完美
preserve anything inside for a
very specific amount of time.
保留里面的任何东西
非常具体的时间。
- How much time, Sandy?
- 桑迪，还有多少时间？
- Oh, I don't know,
like, 2,000-ish years.
- 哦，我不知道，
大约2000年左右。
- Let the ceremony begin.
- 仪式开始吧。
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Mwah!
- 哇！
- I just want to leave a happy
message for the good people
-我只想留下一个快乐
给好人的讯息
of tomorrow.
明天的。
[chortling]
[咯咯笑]
- Ooh, what a fancy trash can.
- 哦，多漂亮的垃圾桶啊。
[loud clarinet music]
[响亮的单簧管音乐]
- Hey, what are you
doing with my clarinet?
- 嘿，你是什么？
我的单簧管在做什么？
- Making it the
future's problem.
- 使其成为
未来的问题。
- Out of my way, Mr. Squidward.
- 让开，章鱼哥先生。
Customers of the future will
pay top dollar for a vintage
未来的客户将
花高价购买葡萄酒
original Krabby Patty.
原来的蟹黄派蒂。
Can I charge for this
now or do I have to wait?
我可以为此收费吗
现在还是我必须等待？
- And that concludes
this momentous occasion.
- 就这样结束了
这个重要的时刻。
Thank you all so much for...
非常感谢大家...
- Not so fast!
- 没那么快！
[crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
- [cackling]
- [咯咯笑]
[crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
- You fools!
- 你们这些傻瓜！
With this patty
in my grasp, I can
有了这个肉饼
在我的掌握中，我可以
finally take over the world!
终于统治世界了！
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
- Yeah, maybe later.
- 是的，也许稍后。
- 2,000 years.
- 2,000 年。
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Much later.
[laughs]
- 很久以后。
[笑]
- Hey, let me out of here!
- 嘿，让我离开这里！
I have to destroy you all.
我必须毁掉你们所有人。
- [chortling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Huh?
- 啊？
No!
不！
Oh, Neptune, no!
哦，海王星，不！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- As I was saying,
thanks for coming, everybody.
- 正如我所说，
谢谢大家的到来。
Free pizza at city hall!
市政厅免费披萨！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Free! Free!
- 自由的！自由的！
- Oh!
Pizza, pizza!
- 哦！
披萨，披萨！
Oh!
哦！
- What have you gotten
yourself into
- 你得到了什么
自己进入
this time, Sheldon?
这次，谢尔顿?
- Karen, get me a can opener
or something, quick.
- 凯伦，给我一个开罐器
或者什么的，快点。
- Well, guess we have to
wait until it opens up.
- 好吧，我想我们必须这样做
等到它打开。
I'll see you later.
稍后见。
[timer ticking]
[计时器滴答作响]
[beep]
[嘟]
- [chortling]
- [咯咯笑]
- At last, after surviving
on this patty one
- 终于，活下来之后
在这个小馅饼上
molecule at a time, I've finally
一次分子，我终于
cracked the secret formula.
破解了秘密配方。
Now my reign of terror can be...
现在我的恐怖统治可以是......
wait a minute.
等一下。
[futuristic beeping]
[未来的嘟嘟声]
This dump looks less dumpy.
这个垃圾场看起来不那么矮胖。
The future must be pretty
great if everything's
未来一定很美好
如果一切都很好就好了
made of chrome, and slidey.
由铬制成，并且很滑。
Hyup.
协。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Hey-ee.
嘿嘿。
Mm, pretty. Ooh.
嗯，漂亮。哦。
What?
什么？
The Chrome Bucket?
镀铬桶？
Whoa.
哇哦。
Where's the door?
门在哪里？
I can't take over the world if
I can't even get into my lab.
如果我无法接管世界
我什至不能进入我的实验室。
Karen, let me in!
凯伦，让我进去！
- Sheldon, welcome home.
- 谢尔顿，欢迎回家。
- Karen, is that you?
- 凯伦，是你吗？
I see you've had some work done.
我看到你已经完成了一些工作。
- Uh-huh.
- 呃哈。
And that's not the only
work I've been doing.
这并不是唯一的
我一直在做的工作。
- Ooh.
- 哦。
Have you completed some kind
of deadly destructive robot?
你完成过某种
致命的破坏性机器人？
- Negative.
- 消极的。
I have been working
on my art pieces.
我一直在工作
在我的艺术作品上。
I'm quite successful, in fact.
事实上，我很成功。
- Oh, honey, this would match
the couch in the living room.
- 哦，亲爱的，这很匹配
客厅的沙发。
- We'll take it.
- 我们会接受的。
- Who cares about art?
- 谁关心艺术？
Time to help me
take over the world.
是时候帮助我了
接管世界。
Now, what happened
to the front door?
现在，发生了什么事
到前门？
Ah, never mind.
啊，没关系。
- You don't
understand, Plankton.
- 你不
明白了，浮游生物。
The whole world
is different now.
整个世界
现在不同了。
- Wait, what do you mean?
- 等等，你什么意思？
- Let me show you.
- Whoa!
- 让我告诉你。
- 哇！
- See?
- 看？
This is Squidward's old house.
这是章鱼哥的老房子。
- Huh? Museum of Squidward?
- 啊？章鱼哥博物馆？
Who would ever go to a museum
dedicated to that loser?
谁会去博物馆
献给那个失败者？
- Lots of people.
- 很多人。
Squidward's old clarinet
recordings are considered
章鱼哥的旧单簧管
录音被考虑
classical music now.
现在古典音乐。
- Wow.
- 哇。
They weren't considered
music at all before.
他们没有被考虑
以前根本没有音乐。
- Sadly, no one
started listening
- 可悲的是，没有人
开始听
to them until the day
after he was gone.
直到那一天
他走后。
- Typical.
- 典型的。
- This is what Patrick's
rock looks like now.
- 这就是帕特里克的
摇滚看起来像现在。
- Ugh.
- 呃。
That moron was always an idiot.
那个白痴始终是个白痴。
And his stupid soda cup left
me sticky for 2,000 years.
他那愚蠢的汽水杯离开了
我粘了2000年。
If he were here
right now, I'd sock
如果他在这里
现在，我会穿袜子
him right in his slack jaw.
他就在他松弛的下巴上。
Eh...
呃……
- And this is the P-1000.
- 这是 P-1000。
- I'm hungry.
- 我饿了。
I need a chrome snack.
我需要一份铬合金零食。
- Even as a robot he's an idiot.
- 即使作为机器人他也是个白痴。
- Food!
- 食物！
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Ew!
- 呃！
This doesn't taste like chrome.
这尝起来不像铬。
I'm going back to bed.
我要回去睡觉了。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Now, let me guess...
现在，让我猜一下...
next, you're going to show me
what happened to SpongeBob.
接下来，你要告诉我
海绵宝宝发生了什么事。
- I wasn't, but if you insist.
- 我不是，但如果你坚持的话。
- Hey, cats.
- 嘿，猫们。
How's it hanging?
挂得怎么样了？
Thanks for stopping by, ya dig?
谢谢你过来，你明白吗？
- Wow, SpongeBob.
- 哇，海绵宝宝。
I can't believe something
here has actually improved,
我无法相信某事
这里确实有所改善，
and that something was you.
那东西就是你。
- It's not SpongeBob.
- 这不是海绵宝宝。
It's his holographic doorman.
这是他的全息门卫。
- [chortling]
- [咯咯笑]
- This is the real SpongeBob,
- 这才是真正的海绵宝宝，
or at least what's left of him.
或者至少是他剩下的东西。
- [chortling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Aww, he likes you.
- 哇，他喜欢你。
- [screams].
- [尖叫]。
Make it stop!
让它停下来！
I was haunted by the echoes
of that laugh
我被回声所困扰
那个笑声
for 2,000 years.
2000 年来。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
♪ ♪
Huh?
啊？
♪ ♪
OK, I get it.
好的，我明白了。
The future is awful.
未来很糟糕。
But I know
the secret formula now.
但我知道
现在的秘密配方。
We can take over
this horrible timeline.
我们可以接管
这个可怕的时间线。
- Um, about that.
- 嗯，关于这个。
I think there's something
else you should see.
我认为有一些东西
否则你应该看看。
- The Kromey Krab?
- 克罗米蟹？
"Permanently closed
due to rust."
“永久关闭
由于生锈。”
This is great news.
这是个好消息。
- Ah, not exactly.
- 啊，不完全是。
It doesn't matter if the
Krusty Krab is open or not.
没关系，如果
蟹堡王是否营业。
In the future, everyone
knows the secret formula.
未来大家
知道秘密公式。
- They what?
- 他们什么？
No!
不！
That's it!
就是这样！
I've had it with the future!
我已经受够了未来！
I just want to go back
to all the people I hate.
我只想回去
致所有我讨厌的人。
- Oh, why didn't you say so?
-哦，你为什么不这么说？
I know someone who
might be able to help.
我认识一个人
或许能帮上忙。
- The screwy squirrel?
Really?
- 古怪的松鼠？
真的吗？
- The squirrel didn't
get trapped in a tube
- 松鼠没有
被困在管子里
for 2,000 years, did she?
2000年了，是吗？
- Touché, I guess.
- Touché，我猜。
This is weird.
这很奇怪。
Sandy's place looks
exactly the same.
桑迪的地方看起来
完全一样。
- Indeed, but be warned.
-确实如此，但请注意。
Sandy may not be exactly
how you remember her.
桑迪可能不完全是
你如何记得她。
- Uh...
- 呃...
- Who dares to
knock upon my dome?
- 谁敢
敲我的圆顶吗？
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
- Hello?
- 你好？
Sandy?
沙？
Are you in there?
- [grunts]
你在里面吗？
- [咕哝]
Hi!
你好！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Sandy Cheeks at your
service, Mr. Plankton.
- 桑迪脸颊在你的
服务，浮游生物先生。
- What the...
how did you get younger?
- 什么...
你是怎么变年轻的？
- Oh, I've just been
jumping through the ages
- 哦，我刚刚
跨越岁月的跳跃
since summer ended
at Kamp Koral.
自从夏天结束以来
在坎普科拉尔。
- Oh, just exploring
space and time, huh?
-哦，只是探索
空间和时间吧？
How wonderful.
多么美妙啊。
Please take me back to
the present, please!
请带我回到
现在，请！
I hate the future.
我讨厌未来。
I hate it!
我恨它！
- [giggles].
- [咯咯笑]。
No need to beg, Mr. Plankton.
没必要乞求，浮游生物先生。
I've been expecting you.
我一直在等你。
The time hopper's all gassed up.
时间跳跃者已经充满了气。
- Well, where is it?
- 那么，它在哪里？
- You're standing
in it, partner.
- 你站着
在其中，伙伴。
This here tree dome is
my reverse time capsule.
这里的树圆顶是
我的逆时空胶囊。
- Then what are we waiting for?
-那我们还等什么？
Away we go!
我们走吧！
[both vocalizing]
[两人都发声]
- So long, Karen!
- 再见，凯伦！
See you 2,000 years ago.
2000年前再见。
- You can come out now,
Plankton 2.0.
- 你现在可以出来了
浮游生物2.0。
- I thought he'd never leave.
- 我以为他永远不会离开。
Now lay some chrome on me, baby.
现在给我涂点铬吧，宝贝。
- [purrs]
- [呼噜声]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[loud bang]
[巨响]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Mwah, mwah, mwah!
哇，哇，哇！
I never thought
I'd say this, but I
我从没想过
我想说这个，但我
missed this horrible place.
错过了这个可怕的地方。
Oh, and thank you
for your help or whatever.
哦，谢谢你
为了你的帮助或者其他什么。
Be gone now.
现在就走吧。
- Ain't you
forgetting something?
- 不是你吗
忘记了什么？
- All right, all right.
- 好吧，好吧。
Can you break a single?
能破单吗？
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
I don't need a tip,
but I will need you
我不需要小费
但我需要你
to forget that secret formula.
忘记那个秘密公式。
Hold still while I activate
my memory-erasing device.
当我激活时请保持不动
我的记忆擦除设备。
- Your what?
- 你的什么？
- See you back at camp,
Mr. Plankton.
- 营地见
浮游生物先生。
[soft music]
[轻音乐]
- Oh.
- 哦。
What happened?
发生了什么？
How did I get here?
我是怎么到这里的？
[groans]
[呻吟]
Huh?
啊？
Aha!
啊哈！
- Customers of the future
will pay top dollar
- 未来的客户
将支付高额费用
for a vintage
original Krabby Patty.
适合年份
原来的蟹黄派蒂。
- A Krabby Patty!
Ho-ho-ho!
- 蟹肉饼！
嗬嗬嗬！
Now's my chance.
现在我的机会来了。
Not so fast!
没那么快！
[crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
- [cackling]
- [咯咯笑]
You fools!
你们这些傻瓜！
Huh?
啊？
Is anyone else having déjà vu?
还有人有似曾相识的感觉吗？
- See you in 2,000-ish
years, Plankton.
- 2000 年后见
年，浮游生物。
[laughs]
[笑]
- 2,000 years.
- 2,000 年。
- Huh?
- 啊？
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
[upbeat country music]
[欢快的乡村音乐]
♪ ♪
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Oh, Gary!
哦，加里！
Breakfast is served.
供应早餐。
- [braying]
- [嘶叫]
- Gary?
- 加里？
Ooh, you sure sound
different this morning.
哦，你确实听起来
今天早上不同。
- [braying]
- Ah!
- [嘶叫]
- 啊！
- [braying]
- [嘶叫]
Oh, it's Narlene's sea mule.
哦，这是纳琳的海骡。
Hey there, buddy.
嘿，伙计。
Did you come to see me?
你来看我了吗？
- [braying]
- [嘶叫]
- Huh.
- 嗯。
"Play me."
“玩我吧。”
- [speaking Nobbese]
Patrick, Sandy, you...
- [讲诺布语]
帕特里克、桑迪，你们……
[speaking Nobbese]
[诺布语]
- Meow?
- 喵？
- Oh, I speak Nobbese.
- 哦，我说诺布语。
I'll translate for you.
我来给你翻译。
[clears throat]
[清嗓子]
Narlene and Nobby invite you,
Patrick, Sandy, and definitely
纳琳和诺比邀请你，
帕特里克、桑迪，当然还有
not Squidward to our
family's Annual Bumble Jelly
不是我们的章鱼哥
家庭年度大黄蜂果冻
Harvest in Bikini Holler.
穿着比基尼的收获。
This recording will
self-destruct in three,
这段录音将
三段自毁，
two, one, ze...
二、一、泽...
Be a good boy, Gary!
做一个好孩子，加里！
I'll be back later!
我稍后回来！
- Meow.
- 喵。
Meow.
喵。
[rock music playing]
[摇滚乐演奏]
♪ ♪
[upbeat country music]
[欢快的乡村音乐]
- ♪ Oh, we're on our
way to Bikini Holler ♪
- ♪ 哦，我们正在我们的
去比基尼大喊的路♪
- [yodels]
- [约德尔调]
-♪ The road behind us
is getting smaller ♪
-♪ 我们身后的路
越来越小了♪
- [yodels]
- ♪ The grass is green ♪
- [约德尔调]
- ♪ 草是绿的 ♪
♪ And the trees are taller ♪
♪ 树更高了 ♪
- [yodels]
- [约德尔调]
♪ And I'll stop yodeling
for just a dollar ♪
♪ 我会停止唱约德尔歌
只要一美元♪
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Why in tarnation
are we stopping?
- 为何陷入困境
我们停下来吗？
Come on, mule.
来吧，骡子。
Get moving.
行动起来吧。
- Look out below!
- 看下面！
- Narlene!
- 纳琳！
Nobby!
诺比！
- In the flesh.
- 在肉体中。
- [speaking Nobbese] flesh.
- [诺布语] 肉体。
- Howdy, Narlene and Nobby.
- 你好，纳琳和诺比。
Seems your mule just
plum stopped moving.
看来你的骡子只是
梅停止了动作。
- Why don't I open her up
and check the engine?
- 为什么我不打开她的心扉
并检查发动机？
- Why do you even
have a head, huh?
- 你为什么还要
有头吧？
- Uh, it keeps the rain
out of my neck hole.
- 呃，它一直在下雨
从我的颈洞里出来。
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
♪ ♪
- [speaking Nobbese] Get in!
- [诺布语] 进来！
- What gives?
- 给什么？
- The mule refuses to walk
through these parts
- 骡子拒绝行走
通过这些部分
'cause this here road
goes right through...
因为这里的路
直接穿过...
- Plankton Territory?
- 浮游生物领地？
- That's right, Planktons.
- 没错，浮游生物。
[spits]
[吐口水]
- "Narwhals keep out"?
- “独角鲸远离”？
Ah!
啊!
- Go home, Narwhals!
- 回家吧，独角鲸！
- This here is Plankton land!
- 这里是浮游生物之地！
- We don't want your fancy
ivory tusks around here!
- 我们不想要你的幻想
这里有象牙！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Let's skedaddle!
我们来溜溜吧！
- Why are they doing this?
- 他们为什么要这样做？
- Planktons and
the Narwhals have
- 浮游生物和
独角鲸有
been feuding for generations.
世世代代都有争斗。
They claim the bumble
jelly fields are theirs
他们声称是笨蛋
果冻田是他们的
while we know they're ours.
虽然我们知道它们是我们的。
- Why don't you
share the fields?
- 你为什么不呢
共享字段？
- Well, where's the fun in that?
- 那么，这有什么乐趣呢？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
♪ ♪
Oh.
哦。
Here we be, bumble jelly fields.
我们在这里，大黄蜂果冻田。
[bumble jellies buzzing]
[大黄蜂果冻嗡嗡作响]
- Whoa.
[laughter]
- 哇哦。
[笑声]
- My brothers there peck the
trees where the bumble jellies
- 我的兄弟们在那里啄食
熊果冻所在的树
store their jelly.
储存他们的果冻。
My sisters over there
like to squeeze it
我的姐妹们在那边
喜欢挤它
fresh right out of the hive.
刚从蜂巢里出来的。
The old folks prefer to serenade
老人们更喜欢听小夜曲
the jelly out of the bumbles.
果冻从大黄蜂中出来。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- SpongeBob, Sandy,
meet our ma and pa.
- 海绵宝宝、桑迪、
认识一下我们的妈妈和爸爸。
- Howdy.
- 你好。
- Say, man, is that pink
city slicker with you?
- 说吧，伙计，那是粉红色的吗
城市里有你吗？
♪ ♪
He sure is brave.
他确实很勇敢。
- Brave?
- Yup.
- 勇敢的？
- 是的。
The only reason
the bumble jellies
唯一的原因
熊果冻
let us collect their
jelly is because we
让我们收集他们的
果冻是因为我们
allow 'em to sting us.
让他们蜇我们吧。
[laughs]
[笑]
- You let them sting you?
- 你让他们蜇你吗？
- Darn tootin'!
- 该死的！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
I consent.
我同意。
- It's worth it.
- 这是值得的。
- Help!
- 帮助！
- There, there, son.
- 那里，那里，儿子。
You gotta hold still
to complete the, uh,
你必须保持不动
完成，呃，
social contract.
社会契约。
Well, now that wasn't
so bad now, was it?
好吧，现在那不是
现在太糟糕了，是吗？
- No, sir.
- 不，先生。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Bumble jelly,
bumble jelly, bumble jelly.
- 大黄蜂果冻，
大黄蜂果冻，大黄蜂果冻。
- I declare that this here
is a bountiful bumper crop
- 我在此声明
是五谷丰登
of beautiful bumble jelly.
美丽的大黄蜂果冻。
[horn blows]
[号角吹响]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Harvest time is over.
- 收获季节结束了。
Let the bumble jelly
festival commence!
让大黄蜂果冻
节日开始！
- [speaking Nobbese] Festival!
- [诺布语] 节日！
♪ ♪
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[trumpet plays]
[喇叭演奏]
♪ ♪
[banjo playing]
[班卓琴演奏]
♪ ♪
- [belches]
- [打嗝]
♪ ♪
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Jelly flop!
- 果冻失败！
- Mm-hmm.
- 嗯嗯。
Good contour.
轮廓好。
Strong structure.
结构坚固。
A very bold mold.
非常大胆的模具。
Hey, why is your cousin
in the long trench coat
嘿，为什么是你表弟
穿着长风衣
tipping over that jelly barrel?
打翻果冻桶？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Wait a sec.
- 等一下。
That ain't no cousin.
那不是表弟。
[all cackling]
[全都咯咯笑]
It's Planktons!
这是浮游生物！
- Planktons!
- 浮游生物！
- Let 'em have it!
- 让他们拥有吧！
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
♪ ♪
- We've got ourselves a feud!
- 我们之间有仇！
Oh!
哦！
Lordy Neptune!
海王星阁下！
I've been spud smacked!
我被马铃薯打了！
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
♪ ♪
- Fire in the hole.
- 洞里着火。
[triumphant organ music]
[胜利的管风琴音乐]
- Yeehaw!
- 耶哈！
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
呼呼呼！
Yeah!
是的！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- What do we do know?
- 我们知道什么？
- Them Planktons can
throw all the potatoes
- 浮游生物可以
把所有的土豆都扔掉
in the ocean at us.
在我们的海洋里。
We've got us something
special that'll
我们有一些东西
特别的那会
give us a decisive victory.
给我们带来决定性的胜利。
- [speaking Nobbese]
Secret weapon.
- [讲诺布语]
秘密武器。
- We need more taters.
- 我们需要更多土豆泥。
- Oh, no!
- 哦，不！
Everyone take cover!
大家都躲起来！
It's shoes!
是鞋子！
[planktons screaming]
[浮游生物尖叫]
- Well, this stinks.
- 嗯，这很臭。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- [yells]
- [大喊]
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
I'm out of shoes.
我没鞋了
We plum tossed 'em all.
我们把它们都扔掉了。
[rhythmic footsteps]
[有节奏的脚步声]
- What's that sound?
- 那是什么声音？
- I don't rightly know.
- 我不太清楚。
Sounds like shoes.
听起来像鞋子。
♪ ♪
- We'd like a truce.
- 我们想要休战。
Ain't no reason
Narwhals and Plankton
不是没有理由
独角鲸和浮游生物
can't share the fields.
无法共享字段。
Besides, we ran
out of ammo thanks
除此之外，我们还跑了
没有弹药了，谢谢
to your tater-eating
city slicker.
给你吃土豆的
城市更光滑。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Nice work, Patrick.
- 干得好，帕特里克。
- It was an honor to serve.
- 能够服务是我的荣幸。
- A truce, eh?
- 休战，嗯？
Well, seeing as how
we're all out of shoes.
嗯，看看如何
我们都没有鞋子了。
- You want 'em back?
- 你想让他们回来吗？
- Oh, heck.
- 哦，哎呀。
You can keep 'em.
你可以保留它们。
Besides, we ain't
found much use for 'em.
此外，我们不是
发现它们有很多用处。
- What happens now?
- 现在会发生什么？
- The annual post-feud party.
- 一年一度的争吵后聚会。
- Annual?
- 年度的？
You mean you do this every year?
你的意思是你每年都这样做？
- Sure do.
- 当然可以。
It's fun.
很有趣。
Why, didn't y'all have fun?
怎么，大家都没玩得开心吗？
- We did not have fun.
- 我们没有玩得很开心。
We had...
我们有...
both: The best day ever!
两人：有史以来最好的一天！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
[upbeat country music]
[欢快的乡村音乐]
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
[vocalizing]
♪ Bumble jelly ♪
[发声]
♪ 大黄蜂果冻 ♪
♪ Bumble jelly ♪
- [vocalizing]
- [发声]
♪ 大黄蜂果冻 ♪
♪ Bumble jelly ♪
- [vocalizing]
- [发声]
Bumble jelly!
大黄蜂果冻！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪